Lilian MARTIN | Data Analyst

martin.lilian4@gmail.com | +33678321070 | 75019, Paris | LinkedIn | Streamlit portfolio

PROFILE SUMMARY

Data Analyst with 4 years of experience complemented by additional skills in data science and engineering. My goal is to work for an ambitious and sustainable company in Sweden. Holding a master's degree in demography and statistics and certified as a data analyst, I am proficient in Python, SQL, and BI tools. I have an autonomous, fast-learner profile with strong communication skills and the ability to adapt to different tasks and environments. If my profile aligns with your requirements, don't hesitate to contact me.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data analyst 2021- 2023

Matrice | Paris

- Production of machine learning models, creation of ETL processes, deep learning.
- Mentoring and management of a junior data scientist.
- Proficient in training design and implementation, I've successfully guided over 50 professionals in their transition to become data analysts and data scientists. My instructional expertise spans a wide range of topics, including statistics, Python programming, SQL, machine learning, API utilization, BI tools, and web scraping techniques.

Reference: Thyfanie Johnson | Matrice (Manager) | thyfaniej@gmail.com

François-Xavier Petit | Matrice (CEO) | fxpetit@matrice.io

Data analyst 2019-2021

Rise Up | Paris

- Development of several customer- and employee-focused 'Datalab'. Creation of dashboards and monthly statistical reports using BI tools such as AWS Quicksight and Google Looker Studio, combined with SQL.
- Communication with stakeholders, taking account of their needs and defining the right KPI's to implement.

Statistical studies manager

2018-2019

CARITAS France Secours Catholique | Paris

- Participation in the writing of two statistical reports (State of poverty in France).
- Collecting, organising, and cleaning the data needed to produce the report (VBA, SAS, Excel).

Volunteer referent | La Base Census investigator | INSEE/ORIVE 2019-2022

2017-2018

HARD SKILLS

- Python | scikit learn | TensorFlow | plotly | pandas | scrapy | SQL | Deployment (Streamlit, Dash, Flask)
- Google Looker Studio | AWS Quicksight | Tableau | Qlik Sense | Dash | ETL process | prompt engineering | Git
- Data cleaning, modelling | inferential statistics | AB testing | Machine learning | Deep learning | scraping | REST APIs

EDUCATION

•	Data engineer Datascientest X Ecole des Mines ParisTech	2023 - 2024
•	Data analyst ENSAE-ENSAI X Open Classrooms	2019 - 2021
•	Master's degree in Demography & statistics Paris 1 Panthéon-Sorbonne	2014 - 2019

STRENGTHS

- At ease in speaking, autonomous, fast learner, emotional intelligence, disciplined, problem solving, decision making
- Hobbies: MMA, Karate, snowboarding, volunteering, hiking, theatre, public speaking